>> Jimmy: HI.
I'M JIMMY KIMMEL.
A
AND TONIGHT'S SHOW IS GOING TO
BE DIFFERENT FROM OUR USUAL
SHOW.
WE DON'T HAVE A STUDIO AUDIENCE
HERE TONIGHT BECAUSE GOING
FORWARD WITH A COMEDY SHOW
DIDN'T FEEL RIGHT CONSIDERING
WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
SO I'D LIKE TO JUST SPEAK TO YOU
DIRECTLY.
AS YOU UNDOUBTEDLY KNOW,
KOBE BRYANT AND HIS DAUGHTER
GIANNA AND SEVEN OF THEIR
FRIENDS WERE KILLED IN A
HELICOPTER CRASH YESTERDAY HERE
IN LOS ANGELES, AND THAT WAS A
PUNCH IN THE GUT FOR MANY OF US.
KOBE WAS, AND I KNOW THIS MIGHT
NOT MAKE SENSE, BUT HE WAS JUST
THE LAST PERSON YOU COULD EVER
IMAGINE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENING TO.
HE WAS SO STRONG AND HANDSOME
AND SMART AND ENERGETIC.
HE WAS A HERO.
AND WHEN I SAY THAT, I DON'T
MEAN A HERO LIKE REAL HEROES
LIKE FIREFIGHTERS OR DOCTORS AND
NURSES WHO ACTUALLY SAVE LIVES.
I DON'T MEAN TO COMPARE WHAT HE
DID FOR A LIVING TO WHAT THEY
DO.
I KNOW THERE ARE MORE IMPORTANT
THINGS THAN BASKETBALL.
ALMOST EVERYTHING IS MORE
IMPORTANT.
BUT KOBE WAS A HERO IN THE WAY
SUPERMAN IS A HERO.
HE WAS SO BIG, IT WAS ALMOST
LIKE HE WAS A FICTIONAL
CHARACTER.
HE WAS A REAL-LIFE SUPERHERO
WITH A COSTUME AND EVERYTHING
WALKING AAMONGST US.
THOSE OF US WHO LOVE THE LAKERS
KNOW IT, IT SEEMS LIKE HE ALWAYS
CAME THROUGH, HE ALWAYS SHOWED
UP TO SAVE THE DAY.
HE WANTED TO SAVE THE DAY.
HE HAD A FORCE OF WILL.
HE NEVER GAVE UP.
AS AN ATHLETE HE WAS INCREDIBLY
GIFTED, MORE THAN ALMOST ANYONE.
HE WAS TALENTED BEYOND REASON.
AND YET HE WORKED HARDER THAN
EVERYONE.
HE WORKED HARDER THAN PEOPLE
WITH MUCH LESS TALENT THAN HE
HAD.
HE TOOK HIS JOB AND HIS PURSUIT
OF EXCELLENCE SO SERIOUSLY, HE
WAS COMPLETELY DEDICATED TO
BEING AS GOOD AS HE POSSIBLY
COULD BE.
WHICH IS INSPIRING TO ANYONE WHO
DOES ANYTHING.
AND WE LOVED HIM BECAUSE OF
THAT.
BUT WE ALSO LOVED HIM BECAUSE HE
WAS OURS.
WE WATCHED HIM GROW UP HERE.
HE CAME TO L.A. WHEN HE WAS A
TEENAGER.
AND UNLIKE ALMOST EVERY OTHER
SUPERSTAR ATHLETE, HE NEVER
LEFT.
IN HIS 20-YEAR CAREER HE ONLY
WORE TWO UNIFORMS, FOR THE
LAKERS AND FOR THE UNITED STATES
OLYMPIC TEAM.
THERE WERE TEAMS WHEN IT SEEMED
LIKE HE WOULD LEAVE, BUT HE
DIDN'T.
HE ZAID UNTIL THE END.
AND HE'S SOMEONE ALMOST EVERYONE
IN THE CITY LOVED.
AND NOT JUST LAKERS FANS.
EVERYONE WOULD LIGHT UP WHEN
THEY SAW HIM.
I SAW MANY TIMES.
HE WAS A SPECIAL PERSON.
A GREAT BASKETBALL PLAYER FOR
SURE, BUT MORE THAN THAT, HE HAD
SO MANY INTERESTS OUTSIDE OF
SPORTS.
HE WAS INTENSELY CURIOUS.
HE WOULD CALL PEOPLE HE ADMIRED
TO INTERVIEW THEM, BUSINESS
LEADERS, WRITERS, INVENTORS.
HE WAS ALWAYS LEARNING, ALWAYS
IMPROVING.
HE HAD A HUNGER FOR THAT.
WHEN HE WAS INJURED, WHEN HE
TORE HIS ACHILLES, I SENT HIM A
BOOK, AND TO MY SURPRISE HE READ
IT AND THEN CALLED ME TO DISCUSS
IT IN MANIACAL DETAIL.
HE WANTED TO KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT IT.
AND I WAS LIKE I DON'T KNOW,
KOBE, I DIDN'T WRITE IT.
I JUST BOUGHT THE BOOK.
AND I HAD TO PUT HIM IN TOUCH
WITH THE GUY WHO WROTE THE BOOK.
AND THAT'S WHAT HE WAS LIKE.
I HAD MANY CONVERSATIONS WITH
KOBE OFF OF TELEVISION.
AND THEY ALWAYS INVOLVED HIS
DAUGHTERS.
ALWAYS.
ONCE HE RETIRED FROM BASKETBALL,
HIS LIFE REVOLVED AROUND THEIR
LIVES.
HE WAS VERY PROUD OF THEM.
HE LOVED BEING A FATHER.
WHEN MY SON HAD HEART SURGERY,
HE CHECKED IN WITH ME
REPEATEDLY.
HE MADE A POINT ONCE BILLY, MY
SON, WAS OUT OF THE HOSPITAL TO
MEET HIM.
HE WANTED TO MEET HIM.
AND FROM TIME TO TIME HE WOULD
CHECK IN TO SEE HOW HE WAS
DOING.
AND YES, I KNOW HE WAS NOT A
PERFECT PERSON.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
MY INTENTION IS NOT TO CANONIZE
HIM OR MAKE JUDGMENTS ABOUT
THINGS I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT.
BUT I WILL SAY HE LOVED HIS
FAMILY, HE WORKED VERY HARD, AND
HE BROUGHT A LOT OF JOY TO A LOT
OF PEOPLE IN THIS CITY AND WE'RE
GOING TO MISS HIM.
AND I HOPE YOU WILL PRAY FOR HIS
DAUGHTER, GIANNA, AND FOR THEIR
MOTHER, VANESSA, FOR THE THREE
GIRLS KOBE LEFT BEHIND WHO LOST
THEIR FATHER AND THEIR SISTER,
AND FOR HIS FRIENDS WHO WERE ON
THAT FLIGHT WITH HIM.
THE ALTOBELLI FAMILY, CHRISTINA
MAUSER'S FAMILY, THE CHESTER
FAMILY, ARAH ZOBAYAN, THE PILOT.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW MUCH THEY
ARE MISSED.
THIS WAS A TERRIBLE LOSS FOR
THOSE FAMILIES AND FOR THE
LAKERS, FOR KOBE'S TEAMMATES,
FOR HIS FANS.
IT'S JUST -- THERE'S NO SILVER
LINING HERE.
IT'S ALL BAD.
IT'S ALL SAD.
HE WAS A BRIGHT LIGHT.
AND THAT'S HOW I WANT TO
REMEMBER HIM.
HE WAS ON THE SHOW 15 TIMES.
WE HAD MANY FUN AND INTERESTING
CONVERSATIONS.
AND TONIGHT WE ARE GOING TO
SHARE SOME OF THOSE TO REMEMBER
HIM.
STARTING WITH WHAT TURNED OUT TO
BE THE LAST INTERVIEW I GOT TO
DO WITH HIM FROM SEPTEMBER OF
LAST YEAR.
>> Jimmy: PLEASE WISH A WARM
TACO TUESDAY TO LAKERS LEGEND
KOBE BRYANT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> I'M GOOD.
>> Jimmy: GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> YOU TOO, MAN.
>> Jimmy: YOU LOOK GOOD.
YOU LOOK GOOD.
>> THANK YOU.
[ CROWD CHANTING "MVP" ]
THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU HEAR THAT A
LOT?
YOU'RE RUNNING AROUND IN TRAFFIC
AND WHATNOT?
>> ALL THE TIME.
>> Jimmy: YOU DO.
>> IT'S AWESOME, THOUGH.
>> Jimmy: COULD BE A 4R09LOT WO.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
CONGRATS.
YOU HAVE ANOTHER DAUGHTER SINCE
YOU WERE LAST HERE.
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: IS SHE TWO MONTHS OLD?
>> YEAH, SHE'S TWO MONTHS OLD.
>> Jimmy: YOU CALL HER KOKO?
>> YEAH.
K-O-K-O.
>> Jimmy: HER MIDDLE NAME IS
KOBE.
AFTER YOU.
>> IT WASN'T MY IDEA.
>> Jimmy: IT WASN'T YOUR IDEA?
>> NO.
VANESSA CAME TO ME AND SAID I'M
THINKING ABOUT NAMING HER KOBE,
MIDDLE NAME.
AND I'M LIKE, UH.
>> Jimmy: YOU HAVE TO EXPLAIN
IT.
>> OKAY.
THEN TIME GOES ON AND SHE'S
LIKE, YOU KNOW, I'M ACTUALLY
GOING TO CHANGE HER MIDDLE NAME.
I'M LIKE WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I DIDN'T THINK YOU WERE TOO HOT
ABOUT IT.
I SAID YOU CAN'T CHANGE IT NOW,
DUDE.
YOU CAN'T GIVE ME A GIFT AND
THEN TAKE IT BACK.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S RIGHT.
>> YOU KNOW?
>> Jimmy: FOUR DAUGHTERS NOW.
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: I THINK IT'S GOOD THAT
YOU HAVE DAUGHTERS.
I FEEL LIKE IF YOU HAD A SON IN
SPORTS IT MIGHT BE TOO MUCH FOR
THAT KID.
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: I DO.
>> MAYBE.
BUT YOU KNOW, LIKE I LOVE HAVING
GIRLS.
>> Jimmy: YEAH.
IT SUITS YOU.
>> THEY'RE AWESOME, MAN.
HAVING A BOY, I THINK MY WIFE
WANTS A BOY MORE SO THAN I DO.
>> Jimmy: I SEE.
INTERESTING.
>> BUT I LOVE MY GIRLS.
SHE KEEPS SAYING STOP SPEAKING
IT INTO EXISTENCE.
I LOVE MY GIRLS.
STOP SAYING THAT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU WANT A BOY.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS KOBE BRYANT
LIKE IN THE DELIVERY ROOM?
DO YOU BRING THE MAMBA MENTALITY
TO THAT?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IF I TRY TO SAY SOMETHING TO
MY LIFE WHEN SHE WAS GIVING
BIRTH, MAN, SHE'D MAMBA
MENTALITY MY ASS UPSIDE MY HEAD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: YOUR OLDEST DAUGHTER
IS NOW HOW OLD?
>> 16.
>> Jimmy: IS SHE DRIVING NOW?
>> SHE IS.
SHE'S LIKE A SEASONED VET, TOO,
MAN.
>> Jimmy: WHY?
>> SHE'S JUST REALLY CALM.
>> Jimmy: OH.
I SEE.
>> BEHIND THE WHEEL.
VERY CALM.
DOESN'T WANT TO LISTEN TO ANY
LOUD OR FAST MUSIC.
SHE'S JUST A VERY SAFE AND LIKE
CAUTIOUS CAREFUL DRIVER.
>> Jimmy: IS THAT JUST WHEN
YOU'RE IN THE CAR OR --
>> NO, NO.
THAT'S ALWAYS, BRO.
LIKE SHE'S JUST ALWAYS VERY
COOL, CALM AND COLLECTED.
I'M VERY PROUD OF HER.
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE VERY LUCKY.
THAT MEANS THE NEXT ONE'S GOING
TO BE A MANIAC BEHIND THE WHEEL.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I ALWAYS SAY IF YOU LOOK AT
THE ELDEST DAUGHTER, SHE'S
ALWAYS LIKE THE CALM,
RESPONSIBLE, THOUGHTFUL ONE.
YOU KNOW?
AND THEN THE SECOND SISTER'S
LIKE A TORNADO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU KNOW, LIKE ELSA AND ANNA.
YEAH, SHE CAN FREEZE THE CITY
AND ALL THAT.
BUT YOU KNOW, SHE'S RESPONSIBLE
ABOUT IT.
AND THEN THERE'S ANNA WHO JUST
JUMPS OFF CLIFFS.
THAT'S CERTAINLY OUR HOUSE.
BUT THEN WE HAVE TWO OTHER ONES.
>> Jimmy: YOUR SECOND OLDEST
DAUGHTER IS GIANNA, SATELLITE.
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: SO SHE REALLY IS LIKE
ANNA.
YOU GAVE HER THE NAME.
>> HOW ABOUT THAT?
>> Jimmy: SHE WAS, AND CORRECT
ME IF I HAVE THIS WRONG, BUT YOU
HAD A GAME AND IT WAS A PLAYOFF
GAME AGAINST THE SUNS.
YOU TIED THE GAME, WENT INTO
OVERTIME, AND THEN YOU SCORED
LIKE SIX SECONDS LEFT.
THEN YOU RACED TO THE DELIVERY
ROOM AND LATER THAT EVENING,
EARLY IN THE MORNING YOUR
DAUGHTER WAS BORN.
>> THAT SOUNDS ABOUT RIGHT.
EITHER THAT NIGHT OR THE DAY
AFTER.
I CAN'T REMEMBER EXACTLY.
>> Jimmy: DID YOU KNOW YOUR WIFE
WAS IN LABOR WHILE YOU WERE
PLAYING THE GAME?
>> NO.
IT DIDN'T HAPPEN DURING THE
GAME.
IT HAPPENED AFTER.
BUT IT WAS LIKE --
>> Jimmy: SO THERE WAS NO
THOUGHT LIKE MAYBE I'LL MISS
THIS ONE AND HEAD HOME?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> INSTEAD OF SENDING THE GAME
TO OVERTIME?
MAYBE OVERTIME'S NOT A GOOD IDEA
IN THE LONG RUN.
YEAH.
NO, FORTUNATELY I WASN'T --
>> Jimmy: YOU WOULD HAVE PLAYED
TEN OVERTIMES IF IT CAME DOWN TO
IT, WOULD YOU NOT?
>> NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE NO DUMMY.
>> HEY, MY MENTALITY UPSIDE MY
HEAD.
>> Jimmy: I SAW YOU DID AN
INTERVIEW AND YOU'RE TALKING,
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE KIND OF GOOFING
AROUND, BUT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
SHAQ AND YOU WERE SAYING --
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT SHAQ, WHO
WAS NOT QUITE AS DRIVEN AS
YOU -- NO ONE'S AS DRIVEN AS YOU
ARE.
BUT YOU INSINUATED THAT IF SHAQ
KEPT HIMSELF IN BETTER SHAPE YOU
WOULD HAVE EVEN MORE RINGS THAN
YOU HAVE ALREADY.
>> RIGHT.
>> Jimmy: AND SHAQ TOOK -- DID
HE TAKE OFFENSE TO THAT?
>> YEAH, I THINK HE DID.
[ LAUGHTER ]
A LITTLE BIT.
BUT HERE'S THE THING, THOUGH.
LIKE IT WAS REALLY A COMPLIMENT.
LIKE PEOPLE MISSED THE WHOLE
FIRST HALF OF THAT.
IN WHICH I SAID HE WAS THE MOST
DOMINANT PLAYER I'VE EVER SEEN.
AND I FELT LIKE HE COULD HAVE
BEEN THE GREATEST OF ALL TIME.
SO PEOPLE KIND OF MISS THAT PART
OF IT.
THEY CAUGHT ON TO THE LAZY PART.
THAT WAS LIKE -- I SAID THAT
TONGUE IN CHEEK.
WE WEREN'T GOING TO WIN 12
RINGS.
BUT IT'S ALL GOOD.
>> Jimmy: WHAT HAPPENS AFTER
THAT?
DO YOU GO OH BOY, I BETTER CALL
HIM?
OR DOES HE CALL YOU?
HOW DOES IT WORK?
>> NO.
I REACH OUT TO HIM.
BECAUSE YOU KNOW, HE'S MORE
SENSITIVE THAN I AM.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: DID YOU TEXT HIM?
>> I DID.
>> Jimmy: WHAT DID YOU SAY IN
THE TEXT?
LIKE HEY, HA, HA, HA, HA?
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> HEY.
I SAID LISTEN, NO HARD FEELINGS?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: IT'S EASY FOR YOU TO
SAY NO HARD FEELINGS.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO INSULTED HIM.
>> WELL, DID I, THOUGH?
I DON'T KNOW.
>> Jimmy: YOU KNOW, YOU SHOULD
HAVE TEXTED "YOU UP?"
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M GOING TO WORK OUT RIGHT
NOW.
YOU WANT TO JOIN IN?
BUT WHAT I DID SAY IS I SAID
I'LL BE TUNING IN TO YOUR SON
PLAYING AT UCLA THIS YEAR.
YOU BETTER SHOOT THE DAMN BALL
30 TIMES.
I BETTER NOT SEE HIM PASS ONCE.
>> Jimmy: AND HE POSTED
PHOTOGRAPHS OF HIMSELF LIKE
DUNKING ON 12 GUYS.
HE'S LIKE DOES THIS LOOK LAZY?
THINGS ARE GOOD.
THINGS ARE OKAY BETWEEN YOU
AGAIN?
>> YEAH, YEAH.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU GUYS EVER HANG
OUT TOGETHER?
>> I DON'T HAVE TIME.
NEITHER DOES HE.
>> Jimmy: TACO TUESDAY.
HAVE YOU BEEN TO TACO TUESDAY?
>> I HAVE NOT.
>> Jimmy: YOU HAVE NOT.
>> WELL, I'VE BEEN LIVING IN
L.A. FOR LIKE 20 YEARS.
I'M MARRIED TO A LATINA.
>> Jimmy: YOU'VE BEEN TO YOUR
OWN TACO TUESDAY.
LeBRON'S TACO TUESDAY THAT HE
LOSES HIS MIND OVER EVERY WEEK.
EVERY WEEK IT'S LIKE A HOLIDAY
HAS HAPPENED.
>> I MEAN, LISTEN, EVERYBODY HAS
THEIR THING, BRO.
>> Jimmy: I'M FINE WITH TACO
TUESDAY.
>> THAT'S GOING TO GET HIM
GOING, IT GETS HIM GOING.
IT'S AWESOME.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU TAKE ANY ROLE
IN ENCOURAGING GUYS LIKE LeBRON,
YOU KNOW, LAKERS FREE AGENTS, TO
COME TO LOS ANGELES?
OTHER THAN MAYBE A TWEET OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
>> NO.
NO, NO.
I STAY AWAY FROM IT.
I'M REAL CLOSE WITH ROB
OBVIOUSLY.
>> Jimmy: ROB PAULINCA.
>> WE TALK AS A SOUNDING BOARD.
>> Jimmy: WOULD YOU BE FINE OR
WOULD HE BE FIRED TO DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
>> I COULD DO THAT.
>> Jimmy: YOU COULD BE HIS
SURROGATE AND YOU COULD ACTUALLY
REACH OUT TO --
>> I COULD BUT I WON'T.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: YOU WON'T.
>> NO.
>> Jimmy: WHY WON'T YOU?
>> WELL, I STAY AWAY FROM THAT
STUFF.
AND LIKE ROB IS -- HE'S MORE
THAN CAPABLE OF HANDLING THE
JOB.
AND ALL THE PRESSURE THAT COMES
ALONG WITH THAT.
AND I'M QUICK TO TELL HIM,
LISTEN, MAN, YOU'RE MY GUY, BUT
YOU DIDN'T GET OUT ON THE COURT
AND SCORE 40 POINTS FOR ME
EITHER.
I'M NOT GOING TO DO YOUR JOB FOR
YOU.
>> Jimmy: DOES HE SAY I WOULD
HAVE IF I COULD?
>> NO, MAN.
WE HAVE A GREAT RELATIONSHIP.
SO WE'LL TALK AND STUFF.
AND YOU KNOW, JUST AS FRIENDS.
BUT NOTHING SERIOUS.
>> Jimmy: WERE YOU SURPRISED
THAT KAWHI LEONARD CHOSE THE
CLIPPERS OVER THE LAKERS?
>> SURE.
>> Jimmy: YOU WERE, YEAH.
>> Jimmy: YOU THOUGHT HE WAS
GOING TO GO TO THE LAKERS.
>> SURE.
>> Jimmy: WHO WILL GO FARTHER IN
THE PLAYOFFS?
THE LAKERS OR THE CLIPPERS THIS
SEASON?
>> UH.
IT DEPENDS.
AND I SAY THAT NOT TO BE KIND OF
CHEEKY ABOUT IT.
BUT LIKE INJURIES HAS PLAYED
SUCH A HUGE PART.
>> Jimmy: LET'S SAY BOTH TEAMS
ARE BEAUTIFULLY HEALTHY FROM
HERE ON OUT.
>> A LOT OF IFS.
>> Jimmy: YEAH, A LOT OF IFS.
YOU KNOW, 'CAUSE INS GOT HURT
BUT LET'S SAY --
>> IS HOUSTON HEALTHY AS WELL?
GOLDEN STATE HEALTHY AS WELL?
>> Jimmy: WE'RE JUST GOING L.A.
TEAMS.
THAT L.A. RIVALRY.
WHO GOES FARTHER?
>> I CAN'T SAY BECAUSE WHAT IF
THEY'RE PLAYING AN INJURED
HOUSTON ROCKETS TEAM AND JAMES
CAN'T PLAY?
OR WHAT IF THEY'RE PLAYING, YOU
KNOW, AN INJURED GOLDEN STATE
TEAM?
>> Jimmy: CAN'T YOU JUST PLAY
ALONG WITH MY GAME?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NO.
NO, I CANNOT.
I CANNOT.
THERE'S TOO MANY VARIABLES, MY
MAN.
LIKE I'VE GOT TO KIND OF THINK
THROUGH THIS THING.
>> Jimmy: THINKING IS OVERRATED,
KOBE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: WE HAD A LOT OF FUN,
AND WE'VE GOT MUCH MORE WITH
KOBE TO SHARE.
AND IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO
REMEMBER KOBE IN A PHILANTHROPIC
WAY, PLEASE MAKE A DONATION TO
KVBFF.ORG, THE KOBE AND VANESSA
BRYANT FAMILY FOUNDATION.
HELP THEM HELP KIDS HERE IN LOS
ANGELES AND ALL OVER THE WORLD.
WHEN WE RETURN, WE WILL SEE KOBE
AND HIS LAKERS TEAMMATES JUST
AFTER THEY WON HIS FOURTH NBA
TITLE BACK IN 2009.
>>> PLAY CENTER?
>> NO, GUARD.
>> GUARD?
>> YES.
>> THAT'S SURPRISING P P I
THOUGHT A MAN OF YOUR SIZE WOULD
PLAY CENTER.
>> WELL, I PLAY WITH MEXICAN
GUYS.
GOOD LUCK.
YOU'RE GOING TO WIN THE
CHAMPIONSHIP.
I'M GOING TO GIVE YOU HIGH FIVE
MEXICAN.
>> OKAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, KOBE BRYANT.
GOOD LUCK.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, MAN.
>> Jimmy: KOBE AND THE LAKERS
WENT ON TO WIN THE FINALS IN
FIVE GAMES AFTER THAT MEXICAN
HIGH FIVE.
VERY WELL DONE, GUILLERMO.
TONIGHT WE'RE REMEMBERING
KOBE BRYANT, WHO ALWAYS MADE
TIME FOR US HERE.
TWO OF THOSE TIMES WERE RIGHT
AFTER THE LAKERS WON THE NBA
TITLE.
THIS ONE WAS IN 2009, AND I LOVE
THIS INTERVIEW BECAUSE EVEN
THOUGH HE WAS VERY SERIOUS ON
THE COURT YOU CAN SEE HOW MUCH
FUN KOBE AND HIS TEAMMATES HAD
OFF OF IT TOO.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
JR
>> Jimmy: THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL
TROPHY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CROWD CHANTING "MVP" ]
THERE YOU GO.
>> I FEEL LIKE WE'RE BACK AT
STAPLES CENTER.
>> Jimmy: WHAT DOES IT FEEL LIKE
TO BE THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN
MVP OF THE NBA?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WELL, IT'S A TREMENDOUS
HONOR.
>> Jimmy: WELL, CONGRATULATIONS,
GUYS.
ALL OF YOU.
THAT IS A BEAUTIFUL TROPHY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I'D LIKE TO SEE ONE OF YOU WELD
THAT ONTO THE FRONT OF YOUR CAR.
YOU KNOW, AS A HOOD ORNAMENT.
>> THAT'S A GOOD IDEA, ACTUALLY.
>> Jimmy: DRIVING AROUND L.A.
WITH THAT.
DO YOU GET TO LIKE BRING THAT
AROUND LIKE THE STANLEY CUP OR
DOES IT GO BACK TO HEADQUARTERS?
>> NO, IT GOES BACK TO
HEADQUARTERS.
>> Jimmy: IT DOES, HUH?
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: IT SEEMS LIKE YOU
SHOULD GET AT LEAST ONE OF THOSE
FOR YOURSELF.
NO?
>> THEY DO LIKE MINI VERSIONS OF
IT, RIGHT?
>> YEAH, SMALL JOINTS.
>> WE GET SMALL ONES.
>> THEY DON'T OFFER THEM,
THOUGH.
WE HAVE TO PURCHASE THEM.
>> Jimmy: YOU DO?
REALLY?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> REALLY?
>> YEAH.
>> WELL, MAYBE YOU WOULDN'T.
YOU GOT ONE WHEN YOU LEFT ARENA.
>> Jimmy: WELL, WE'LL TAKE UP A
COLLECTION.
YOU GUYS DESERVE IT, CERTAINLY.
IT WAS A GREAT -- WELL, THE
FINALS WEREN'T SO -- IT WAS
GREAT FOR YOU GUYS.
IT WASN'T SO GREAT FOR THE
ORLANDO MAGIC.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PREDICTED YOU'D
WIN IN SIX GAMES.
>> RIGHT.
>> Jimmy: YOU WON IN FIVE GAMES.
DO YOU FEEL LIKE YOU
DISAPPOINTED HIM?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NO.
>> Jimmy: NO, YOU DON'T.
>> AS LONG AS THE OUTCOME
REMAINED CONSISTENT IT'S ALL
GOOD.
>> Jimmy: IT'S A FUNNY THING.
WHEN OBAMA MAKES A PREDICTION
THE OTHER TEAM'S COACH ALWAYS
GETS MAD AND SAYS HE SHOULD HAVE
BETTER THINGS TO BE
CONCENTRATING ON THAN WHO'S
GOING TO WIN THE GAME.
BUT WERE YOU GUYS EXCITED?
OBAMAS ALMOST ALWAYS RIGHT.
HE 3IKD THE STEELERS IN THE
SUPER BOWL.
HE'S REALLY -- HE COULD BE A
HANDICAPPER IF HE WASN'T THE
PRESIDENT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HE'S THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT?
>> Jimmy: I GUESS SO.
NOW, DEREK, YOU OFF THE RECORD
SAID YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN NAMED
MVP.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU SAID YOU'D BEEN CARRYING
KOBE TOO LONG.
[ LAUGHTER ]
LET'S LOOK AT THOSE THREE-POINT
SHOTS IN I THINK GAME 4.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> PUTS UP THE THREE.
[ CHEERS AN
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THERE'S MORE.
THIS GUY RIGHT HERE HAS A PAIR
OF THE BIGGEST COJONES WHEN IT
COMES TO SHOOTING BIG SHOTS,
MAN.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
>> Jimmy: YOU WOULD THINK SO
BECAUSE YOU MISSED FIVE
THREE-POINTERS.
YOU WERE 0 FOR 5 SO FAR.
DO YOU HESITATE AT ALL AFTER --
>> NO.
THANKS FOR BRINGING UP THE BAD
PART, JIMMY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: BUT IN A WAY IT'S THE
GOOD PART.
BECAUSE IF I WENT 0 FOR 5 --
WELL, I WOULD GO 0 FOR 8 TO BE
HONEST.
BUT IF I MISSED FIVE IN A ROW I
THINK I'D JUST SAY HEY, SOMEBODY
ELSE, YOU GET A CHANCE.
>> YEAH.
NO, NO.
THESE GUYS RIGHT HERE, MAN, AND
THE GUYS THAT WILL BE OUT LATER.
THEY'RE ALWAYS WITH ME.
YOU KNOW, SO I'M ALWAYS
CONFIDENT NO MATTER WHAT'S GOING
ON.
I KNOW I'M GOING TO COME THROUGH
FOR MY GUYS.
THEY'VE COME THROUGH FOR ME SO
MANY TIMES.
>> Jimmy: PAU, YOU ARE FROM
SPAIN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
SOMETHING THAT'S BOTHERING ME.
YOUR NAME IS LIKE A BATMAN SOUND
EFFECT.
POW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
I GOT YOU A LETTER L.
YOU PUT IT AT THE END OF YOUR
NAME.
AND YOU'LL BE PAUL FROM NOW ON.
AND I THINK IT WILL MAKE IT
EASIER FOR US AS AMERICANS.
>> IT KEEPS IT UNIQUE.
I LIKE THE UNIQUENESS.
>> Jimmy: YOU LIKE THE
UNIQUENESS?
>> WE'VE GOT TO CLARIFY
SOMETHING, THOUGH.
BECAUSE HE WON'T SAY IT.
OKAY?
HIS NAME IS PAU.
HIS NAME IS NOT PAUL.
IT'S PAU.
THANK YOU.
EVERYBODY SAYS PAUL.
>> Jimmy: I'M SAYING IF YOU JUST
TAKE THIS L HE CAN BE PAUL.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IT MAKES IT A LOT EASIER,
THOUGH.
>> I LIKE IT WITHOUT THE L.
>> PAUL GASOL?
>> Jimmy: PAUL GASOL.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU GET BACK
TO SPAIN?
WILL THERE BE A PARADE FOR YOU?
DID EVERYBODY WATCH THE --
>> THEY DID WATCH.
I'M SO PROUD OF EVERYONE IN
SPAIN BECAUSE WITH THE TIME
CHANGE IT'S SO HARD, 3:00, 4:00
IN THE MORNING WAKE UP AND WATCH
THE GAME AND WATCH US PLAY.
THEY WERE SO EXCITED AND SO
THRILLED WE WERE ABLE TO GET
THIS AMAZING TROPHY.
>> Jimmy: WILL WOMEN THERE BE
ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT MAKING LOVE
TO YOU WHEN YOU GET BACK?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M NOT QUITE SURE.
>> THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION,
JIMMY.
>> I'M NOT QUITE SURE ABOUT
THAT.
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE NOT SURE.
THERE'S A WAY TO FIND OUT.
AND TREVOR, YOU PLAYED FOR THE
ORLANDO MAGIC.
>> I DID.
>> Jimmy: DOES IT MAKE IT MORE
FUN TO BEAT THEM SINCE THESE ARE
THE GUYS YOU PLAYED WITH OR IS
IT --
>> MAN.
>> Jimmy: -- LESS FUN?
>> COME ON, TREVOR.
>> MAN, TO BEAT THEM, ESPECIALLY
ON THEIR HOME FLOOR, WAS AN
UNDESCRIBABLE FEELING.
>> Jimmy: REALLY?
>> YEAH.
THAT WAS THE TEAM THAT TRADED ME
AWAY.
YOU KNOW.
SO TO COME HOME AND BEAT THEM --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: I WANT TO SHOW ONE
OTHER KEY PLAY FROM THAT SAME
GAME.
I THINK IT'S FROM GAME 4 HERE.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
>> WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT IS HE DOING?
NO, REALLY.
>> EXERCISING.
>> WHAT IS HE DOING?
>> Jimmy: KOBE AND THE LAKERS
WON THE TITLE AGAIN THE NEXT
YEAR, BEATING THEIR ARCH-RIVALS
THE BOSTON CELTICS.
AND THAT ONE WAS ESPECIALLY
SWEET.
AND WE WILL HAVE THAT INTERVIEW
FROM 2010 WHEN WE COME BACK.
>>> YOU PLAYED WITH DENNIS
RODMAN FOR A SHORT TIME.
DO YOU THINK HE IS THE SOLUTION
TO OUR PROBLEM WITH NORTH KOREA?
[ LAUGHTER ]
DO YOU THINK HE IS THE GUY TO GO
OVER THERE AND --
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S A CRAZY WORLD,
MAN.
YOU NEVER KNOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHO THE HELL KNOWS?
>> Jimmy: WOULD YOU GO OVER
THERE AND FOCUS ON STOPPING THIS
POTENTIAL NUCLEAR WARHEAD THAT'S
COMING OVER?
THAT SEEMS MORE IMPORTANT THAN
THE GAME.
>> YEAH, I'D PROBABLY PASS.
>> Jimmy: WOULD YOU PASS ON THAT
ONE?
OH, FOR ONCE YOU'RE PASSING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: WE HAD A LOT OF LAUGHS
OVER KOBE'S MANY APPEARANCES ON
OUR SHOW.
THIS INTERVIEW IS FROM 2010 WHEN
THE LAKERS AVENGED THEIR LOSS
TWO YEARS EARLIER TO THE BOSTON
CELTICS.
AND KOBE AND HIS TEAMMATES WERE
IN VERY, VERY GOOD SPIRITS IN
THE HOURS BEFORE THE VICTORY
PARADE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Jimmy: IT'S GREAT TO HAVE YOU
GUYS HERE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANKS FOR COMING.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GREAT TO
HAVE YOU GUYS HERE.
THANKS FOR COMING.
WHO STAYED UP THE LATEST LAST
NIGHT?
JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> Jimmy: RON, ARE YOU WEARING
YOUR EARPIECE?
>> YEAH.
I STILL DIDN'T GO TO SLEEP YET.
YOU STILL HAVEN'T TAKEN A
SHOWER.
I AIN'T GOING TO LIE.
I NEED A SHOWER BAD.
>> I KNEW I SMELLED SOMETHING.
>> Jimmy: YOU DIDN'T GO TO SLEEP
ALL NIGHT SINCE LAST NIGHT?
>> I MEAN, THESE GUYS PUT ME
THROUGH SOME TYPE OF EMOTIONAL
ROLLER COASTER AND HELPED ME GET
MY FIRST RING, AND I JUST CAN'T
SLEEP.
>> Jimmy: WOW.
THAT IS SOMETHING ELSE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I'M GOING TO BE TOTALLY HONEST
WITH YOU.
WHEN RON CAME TO THE TEAM LAST
YEAR, I THOUGHT OH, NO, THIS IS
TERRIBLE, IT'S GOING TO SCREW
EVERYTHING UP.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I SAID RON'S A GREAT PLAYER
OBVIOUSLY BUT RON'S CRAZY, RON'S
A CRAZY PERSON.
AND THEN SURE ENOUGH I WAS
WRONG.
AND RON, YOU'VE BEEN -- I MEAN,
RON, YOU DIDN'T TWITTER -- YOU
DIDN'T TWEET THROUGH THE WHOLE
SERIES.
YOU WERE --
>> I CAN'T LET KOBE DOWN.
NO, DON'T SAY "AW."
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S LIKE -- THAT'S IT.
>> Jimmy: I WANT TO SAY I'M
SORRY TO HEAR PAU GOT DEPORTED.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I HAD A FEELING THAT WAS GOING
TO HAPPEN.
KOBE, YOU SAID A COUPLE OF TIMES
DURING THE SERIES, YOU SAID THAT
IT DIDN'T MATTER THAT IT WAS THE
CELTICS, THAT IT WAS A SERIES
AND IT MADE NO DIFFERENCE.
IN FACT, LET'S SHOW THAT
VIDEOTAPE.
>> WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO YOU TO
BE IN THE GAME 7 IN THE FINALS
AND ESPECIALLY AGAINST THE
CELTICS?
>> NO DIFFERENCE TO ME.
I HATE TO BE A BUZZ KILL, BUT
IT'S NOT.
>> Jimmy: YOU WERE LYING, RIGHT?
THAT WAS A LIE, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU CAN'T LET THESE GUYS WIN.
LOOK AT THIS GUY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: TWO YEARS AGO -- AND I
KNOW.
I SPOKE TO YOU ABOUT THIS.
YOU WERE VERY UPSET THE CELTICS
BEAT YOU.
AS A LAKER YOU'VE GOT TO BEAT
THE CELTICS.
THAT'S A VERY IMPORTANT THING.
AND I KNOW YOU RESPECT THE
HISTORY OF THE FRANCHISE.
AND YOU WERE -- HONESTLY I WOULD
HAVE BET MY HOUSE, MY CAR,
EVERYTHING -- MY CHILDREN, ET
CETERA.
YOU THAT WERE GOING TO WIN.
BECAUSE WHEN WE SPOKE ABOUT IT
YOU WERE SO SERIOUS AND SO
INTENSE ABOUT IT.
IT SCARED ME A LITTLE.
>> WE WERE UPSET.
DEREK AND I --
>> Jimmy: DEREK DIDN'T CARE AS
MUCH I DON'T THINK.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
HE SITS HERE, HE LOOKS SO WELL
MANNERED AND ALL THIS.
HE'S GOT A QUICKER TEMPER THAN I
DO.
>> Jimmy: FOR REAL?
YOU DO?
I KNOW YOU GAVE MORE THAN ONE
INSPIRATIONAL SPEECH TO THE TEAM
BEFORE AND DURING GAME 7.
>> YEAH.
DURING GAME 7.
>> Jimmy: WHAT DID YOU SAY?
WHAT DID HE SAY TO THESE GUYS?
>> JUST DRIED TO KEEP REMINDING
GUYS THAT, I MEAN, WHATEVER
HAPPENED IN THE GAME SO FAR WE
CAN'T PLAY ANY WORSE THAN WHAT
WE'VE BEEN PLAYING.
SO LET'S JUST -- LET'S JUST
RELAX --
>> A VERY DEMOCRATIC WAY TO SAY
YOU GUYS ARE PLAYING LIKE A
BUNCH OF IDIOTS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: WHERE IS ADAM
MORRISON?
BECAUSE HE WAS IN A SUIT PRETTY
MUCH THE WHOLE TIME.
AND I THOUGHT IT WOULD BE FUNNY
IF HE CAME OUT IN A UNIFORM FOR
ONCE.
YOU KNOW?
LFR
>> ADAM ACTUALLY -- HE'S ONE OF
OUR FAVORITE TEAMMATES OF ALL
TIME.
>> Jimmy: HE LOOKS LIKE A '70s
PORN STAR NOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
RIGHT?
HE'S GOT A -- HE LOOKS LIKE HE
STEPS RIGHT OUT OF "BOOGIE
NIGHTS" OR SOMETHING.
I'M SORRY ADAM DIDN'T COME
BECAUSE I FEEL LIKE HE -- MAYBE
NOT ON THE COURT AS MUCH BUT WE
HAVE A LITTLE VIDEO PRESENTATION
I'D LIKE YOU GUYS TO LOOK AT,
AND WE HAVE A MONITOR RIGHT
HERE.
ADAM MORRISON'S CONTRIBUTION TO
THE NBA FINAL SERIES.
>> OH, MAN.
♪
>> ADAM TRIES TO KEEP IT ALIVE.
STOLEN BY BRYANT.
BAD PASS.
THREE!
♪
>> Jimmy: THERE YOU GO.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
EVERYONE PLAYS A PART.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
FIRST OF ALL, LET ME JUST SAY
THAT WAS FUNNY AS HELL.
[ LAUGHTER ]
BUT SECONDLY, LET ME JUST SAY
THAT, YOU KNOW, THAT'S A
TESTAMENT TO OUR TEAM.
HONESTLY.
BECAUSE ADAM CAN REALLY PLAY.
NO, LIKE REALLY.
HE CAN REALLY, REALLY GO.
AND FOR HIM TO TAKE A STEP BACK
AND TO DO THINGS LIKE THAT
REALLY HELPED US GET TO THAT
CHAMPIONSHIP LEVEL.
SO, YEAH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: NOW, THIS IS MY
FAVORITE MOVE FROM LAST NIGHT.
WE HAVE VIDEOTAPE HERE.
WATCH THIS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> YOU SHOULD SEE HIM BEFORE
GAMES.
>> Jimmy: IS THAT RIGHT?
>> HOLD ON.
>> THAT'S --
>> HIM AND PAU BOTH IN THE
MIRROR.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> Jimmy: WHEN WE COME BACK, WE
WILL GO BACK TO 2008, WHEN KOBE
BROUGHT AN OLYMPIC GOLD MEDAL
BACK HOME TO LOS ANGELES.
>>> YOU MAY WANT TO CHANGE IT
OUT.
JUST PUT THAT RIGHT --
>> THAT'S SO SWEET.
>> Jimmy: OSCAR DOESN'T HAVE
ARMS.
THERE YOU GO.
>> Jimmy: KOBE WON AN OSCAR IN
2018.
HE EARNED FIVE RINGS WITH THE
LAKERS AND WAS A TWO-TIME
OLYMPIC GOLD MEDALIST TONIGHT WE
ARE REMEMBERING OUR MUCH TOO
BRIEF TIME WITH HIM.
THIS CLIP, WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO
SEE, IS FROM ONE OF HIS FIRST
APPEARANCES ON OUR SHOW AFTER HE
LED TEAM U.S., THE REDEEM TEAM
AS THEY CALLED IT, TO VICTORY AT
THE 2008 SUMMER GAMES.
>> CONGRATULATIONS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: WHAT AN EXCITING
THING.
[ CROWD CHANTING "MVP" ]
>> FEELS GOOD TO BE HOME.
>> Jimmy: IS IT POSSIBLE EVER TO
GET TIRED OF HEARING THAT?
>> NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: I WOULDN'T THINK SO.
>> NO, ABSOLUTELY NOT.
>> Jimmy: I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO BRING THE GOLD MEDAL.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT I?
ACTUALLY DID.
>> Jimmy: OH, YOU DID?
>> I DID.
I HAVE IT HERE IN MY POCKET.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
IS THERE A DRUM ROLL?
[ DRUM ROLL ]
>> Jimmy: WOW.
LOOK AT THAT.
>> THERE IT IS.
>> Jimmy: NOT BAD.
CAN I HAVE A LOOK AT IT?
WOW.
THAT IS SOMETHING SPECIAL.
I DON'T THINK IT'S A GOOD IDEA
TO KEEP IT IN YOUR POCKET,
THOUGH, BECAUSE IT WILL WIND UP
IN THE HAMPER OR SOMETHING.
>> OH, NO, NO, NO.
>> Jimmy: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
THIS.
THAT IS REALLY VERY NICE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SECURITY!
>> Jimmy: AND PRESIDENT BUSH WAS
AT THE -- HE WAS IN THE LOCKER
ROOM WITH YOU GUYS IT LOOKS LIKE
HERE.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> Jimmy: WHAT WAS HE UP TO
THERE?
>> NO, HE CAME AND GAVE US HIS
SUPPORT.
>> Jimmy: DID HE THREATEN YOU
GUYS?
>> NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
ONE OF OUR PLAYERS, I'M NOT
GOING TO NAME NAMES, ASKED HIM
IF HE HAD ANY FREE GAS CARDS.
>> Jimmy: IS THAT RIGHT?
>> RIGHT.
I WON'T DIME HIM OUT.
>> Jimmy: WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HE'S JUST BRINGING IT IN WITH
US.
>> Jimmy: EITHER THEY
REACTIVATED JOHN STOCKTON OR
THAT SEEMS TO BE THE PRESIDENT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I DON'T THINK HE HAD ON THE
LITTLE SHORTS THAT STOCKTON USED
TO.
>> Jimmy: WELL, THAT IS
SOMETHING ELSE.
HE WAS A CHEERLEADER AT ONE
TIME.
I GUESS IT'S APPROPRIATE.
HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS NOW?
>> 5 AND 2.
>> Jimmy: AND DID THEY GET YOU A
PRESENT FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY?
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
BEFORE THE GOLD MEDAL GAME OUR
OLDEST DAUGHTER, NATALIA, DREW A
PICTURE OF A GOLD MEDAL.
YOU KNOW, WITH THE RIBBON AND
SAID GOOD LUCK.
I TOOK IT WITH ME IN THE LOCKER
ROOM.
ROOM BEFORE THE GAME AND PUT IT
UP AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYBODY CAME AND TOOK A LOOK
AT IT.
>> Jimmy: YOU'D HATE FOR HER TO
BREAK HER CRAYONS OUT AND MAKE
IT SILVER AFTERWARD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THE THING ABOUT KIDS, MAN, IS
THAT YOU DON'T WANT TO
DISAPPOINT THEM.
BEFORE THE GAME THEY'RING DO THE
NATIONAL ANTHEM.
I LOOK UP IN THE STANDS AND I
SEE MY WIFE AND OUR DAUGHTERS.
AND THEY'RE LIKE SINGING USA.
THEY HAVE THE FLAG AND
EVERYTHING.
YOU'RE JUST LOOKING AT THEM AND
YOU'RE LIKE MAN, I BETTER NOT F
THIS UP.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YOU HEAR THE NATIONAL ANTHEM
PLAYING YOU CAN'T HELP BUT GET A
LITTLE EMOTIONAL.
>> Jimmy: WELL, WHEN WE COME
BACK, ONE OF MY FAVORITE
INTERVIEWS WITH KOBE, ONE IN
WHICH HE TALKS ABOUT LeBRON,
COACHING HIS DAUGHTER'S
BASKETBALL TEAM, AND WHAT HE
CALLED THE MAMBA MENTALITY.
>> Jimmy: TONIGHT WE ARE LOOKING
BACK AT MOMENTS WE SHARED WITH
KOBE BRYANT, ONE OF THE GREATEST
PLAYERS IN THE HISTORY OF THE
NBA.
AND KOBE WAS A BASKETBALL
PLAYER.
HE WAS AN AUTHOR TOO.
KOBE WAS IN RELENTLESS PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
IN THIS CONVERSATION FROM 2018
WE TALKED ABOUT MANY THINGS.
HIS DAUGHTERS, LeBRON, HIS BOOK
"THE MAMBA MENTALITY."
AND I THINK THIS CLIP DOES A
VERY GOOD JOB OF ILLUSTRATING
KOBE'S NEVER RESTING COMMITMENT
TO BEING THE BEST HE COULD
POSSIBLY BE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> I'M GREAT.
>> Jimmy: EVERYBODY'S EXCITED TO
SEE YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THAT'S GOT TO BE -- WELL, YOU'RE
BELOVED.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: HOW ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
>> EVERYTHING'S GOOD, MAN.
>> Jimmy: ENJOYING RETIREMENT?
IS IT FUN?
>> I'M ENJOYING RETIREMENT.
>> Jimmy: I KNOW YOU'RE DOING A
LOT OF OTHER THINGS.
>> YEAH.
BUT IT'S FUN.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU WATCH THE
LAKERS?
HAVE YOU BEEN SITTING AND
WATCHING THE GAMES?
>> I WATCHED THE LAST EIGHT
MINUTES OF THE FOURTH QUARTER
AND OVERTIME LAST NIGHT.
MY TEAM, MY GIRLS, WE PRACTICE
EVERY NIGHT WITH MY TEAM.
SO I DON'T GET A CHANCE TO WATCH
THE GAME --
>> Jimmy: YEAH, YOU'RE COACHING.
>> I AM COACHING.
>> Jimmy: HOW MANY GAMES IN A
ROW WOULD THE LAKERS HAVE TO
LOSE FOR YOU TO UNRETIRE, FOR
YOU TO COME BACK TO THE TEAM?
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
IT WOULD BE LIKE -- I MEAN, IF
IT GOT TO LIKE --
>> Jimmy: IF IT GOT TO 20, YOU
WOULD THINK ABOUT IT, RIGHT?
>> IF THEY GO 0-5 I'LL THINK
ABOUT IT.
>> Jimmy: YOU'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
>> NO, I WON'T.
>> Jimmy: LeBRON MAY TANK THOSE
GAMES JUST TO GET YOU ON THE
COURT.
HOW INVOLVED WERE YOU IN LeBRON
COMING TO L.A.?
DID YOU SPEAK TO HIM?
>> NO, I DIDN'T SPEAK TO HIM
ABOUT COMING TO L.A.
BUT I SPEAK TO JEANIE AND --
>> Jimmy: TO JEANIE BUSS.
>> JEANIE BUSS.
>> Jimmy: THE OWNER OF THE TEAM.
>> SHE WANTED TO GET LeBRON
HERE.
BUT LeBRON'S NOT GOING TO COME
HERE IF MANAGEMENT ISN'T FIGURED
OUT.
>> Jimmy: GOT YOU.
>> YOU HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
MANAGEMENT, YOU HAVE TO MAKE
SURE THAT THINGS ARE CLEAN,
THINGS ARE FOCUSED GOING
FORWARD, IT'S NOT CHAOTIC AS IT
HAS BEEN IN YEARS PAST.
AND SHE DID THAT.
>> Jimmy: AND NOW YET HERE WE
ARE.
YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT YOUR OWN
TEAM.
YOU'RE COACHING YOUR DAUGHTER'S
>> I AM.
THEY'RE DOING WELL, THOUGH.
WE'VE BEEN PLAYING FOR LIKE A
YEAR AND A HALF.
>> Jimmy: WHAT'S THEIR RECORD?
>> THEY DON'T HAVE SEASONS.
IT'S CRAZY.
THEY JUST HAVE TOURNAMENTS.
LIKE EVERY WEEKEND.
>> Jimmy: I SEE.
AND IF THEY DON'T WIN THE
TOURNAMENTS DO YOU LIKE -- DO
THEY HAVE TO SLEEP IN THE YARD
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NO FOOD FOR A WEEK.
>> Jimmy: BECAUSE IF ANYONE,
ANYONE WOULD THINK LIKE THAT I
WOULD THINK IT WOULD BE THE
MAMBA MENTALITY.
>> RUNNING FOR TWO HOURS
STRAIGHT IN PRACTICE.
NO WATER BREAKS.
NOTHING.
PUSH-UPS AND SIT-UPS ALL DAY.
>> Jimmy: HOW SERIOUS DO YOU
GET?
ARE YOU GUYS BREAKING DOWN GAME
FILM?
>> NOT YET, BUT WE WILL.
WE ABSOLUTELY WILL.
WE TRY TO TEACH THE KIDS WHAT
EXCELLENCE LOOKS LIKE.
IT'S NOT THAT -- YOU KNOW, SOME
OF THEM MAY WANT TO PLAY IN THE
WNBA.
SOME OF THEM MAY NOT.
>> Jimmy: RIGHT.
>> BUT WE TRY TO GIVE THEM A
FOUNDATION OF THE AMOUNT OF WORK
AND PREPARATION THAT IT TAKES TO
BE EXCELLENT.
IN WHATEVER IT IS THAT YOU
CHOOSE TO DO.
WE'RE HERE PLAYING BASKETBALL,
WE'RE GOING TO FOCUS ON THE
DETAILS, WE'RE GOING TO LEARNT
BASICS, WE'RE GOING TO LEARN THE
FUNDAMENTALS.
WE'RE GOING TO DO THOSE THINGS
OVER AND OVER.
AND HOPEFULLY IT'S SOMETHING
THEY CAN APPLY TO OTHER AREAS IN
THEIR LIFE.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU THINK YOUR
DAUGHTER MIGHT WANT TO PLAY IN
THE WNBA?
>> SHE DOES FOR SURE.
>> Jimmy: SHE DOES?
>> THIS KID, MAN.
>> Jimmy: WOULDN'T THAT BE
GREAT?
>> DUDE, MAN.
I'M TELLING YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THE BEST THING THAT HAPPENS IS
WHEN WE GO OUT AND FANS WILL
COME UP TO ME AND SHE'LL BE
STANDING NEXT TO ME AND THEY'LL
BE LIKE, YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE A
BOY.
YOU AND V GOT TO HAVE A BOY,
MAN.
BE?
TO CARRY ON YOUR TRADITION, THE
LEGACY.
SHE'S LIKE, "OY.
I GOT THIS."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THAT'S RIGHT.
YES, YOU DO.
YOU GOT THIS.
>> Jimmy: HOW OLD ARE THE KIDS
NOW?
>> 15, 12, AND OUR LITTLE ONE
BIANKA, WILL BE 2.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU GUYS HAVE
HALLOWEEN COSTUMES FIGURED OUT?
>> THEY'VE GOT MINE FIGURED OUT.
I NEVER KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
THEY JUST TELL ME THIS IS WHAT
YOU'RE WEARING.
I'M PUTTING THIS ON.
>> Jimmy: WILL YOU TRICK OR
TREAT?
>> WE GO TRICK OR TREATING EVERY
HALLOWEEN.
>> Jimmy: SO YOU'RE IN A
COSTUME.
WHAT WERE YOU LAST YEAR?
>> LAST YEAR WE WERE A LEAGUE OF
THEIR OWN.
SO I WAS THE BLACK TOM HANKS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
NO CRYING IN BASEBALL.
SHE'S CRYING, SIR.
>> Jimmy: I WENT THROUGH THE
BOOK.
BOY.
I WAS JUST PLANNING TO KIND OF
FLIP THROUGH IT BEFORE YOU CAME
ON, AND I GOT REALLY INVESTED IN
IT.
>> THAT'S GOOD.
>> Jimmy: BECAUSE YOU GO
THROUGH -- WELL, FIRST OF ALL,
YOU'RE A LUNATIC.
>> 100%.
>> Jimmy: THERE'S NO TWO WAYS
ABOUT IT.
>> 100%.
>> Jimmy: YOU ALWAYS HEAR ABOUT
YOUR PREPARATION AND ALL THESE
THINGS YOU DO.
BUT WHEN YOU READ THE SPECIFICS
IT'S LIKE OH, MY GOD, THIS IS A
MENTAL PATIENT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IT'S TRUE.
IT'S TRUE.
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE AWARE OF THAT.
WERE YOU ALWAYS AWARE OF THAT?
>> I AM SELF-AWARE OF MY LUNACY,
YES.
>> Jimmy: ONE OF THE THINGS I
THOUGHT WAS MOST INTERESTING IN
THE BOOK IS THAT YOU READ -- AND
THIS GOES BACK TO THE LUNATIC
THING.
YOU READ THE REFEREE'S OFFICIAL
HANDBOOK TO FIND OUT WHERE THE
REFEREES ARE ON THE COURT --
EXPLAIN THIS IDEA.
>> THERE'S A RULEBOOK AND THE
OFFICIALS HAVE TO BE IN CERTAIN
POSITIONS.
SO IF YOU WATCH A GAME YOU'LL
SEE OFFICIALS SLIDING IN
DIFFERENT AREAS.
YOU HAVE YOUR SLOT OFFICIAL AND
SO FORTH AND SO ON.
SO I READ IT TO UNDERSTAND WHERE
THEY NEED TO BE IN CERTAIN
MOMENTS IN TIME SO IF I NEED TO
GET AWAY WITH A FOUL --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THE SLOT OFFICIAL'S NOT GOING TO
SEE THIS LITTLE HOLD HERE.
>> Jimmy: HAS ANY PLAYER THAT
YOU KNOW OF EVER DONE THAT
BEFORE?
>> NOT THAT I KNOW OF.
>> Jimmy: THAT IS INTERESTING.
IN ORDER TO PROTECT -- AND
CORRECT ME IF I HAVE ANY OF THIS
WRONG.
IN ORDER TO PROTECT YOUR ANKLES,
YOU LEARNED TO TAP DANCE.
>> I DID.
>> Jimmy: WHY DIDN'T WE KNOW
THIS?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WELL, IT WAS KEPT SECRET FOR
OBVIOUS REASONS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: DO THEY MAKE TAP SHOES
IN YOUR SIZE?
>> I HAD TO GET THEM MADE.
>> Jimmy: HAD TO GET THEM MADE.
>> I CAN'T GO TO THE STORE AND
BE LIKE, YEAH, I'LL TAKE THOSE
SIZE 14s TAP.
>> Jimmy: YOU CAN'T CALL NIKE
AND SAY DO YOU GUYS HAVE TAP
SHOES.
SO ARE YOU AN ACCOMPLISHED
TAPPER?
DO YOU KNOW HOW TO TAP?
YOU'RE NOT.
>> NO.
BUT ONE SUMMER -- FOR A YEAR
THERE, YEAH.
I COULD TELL MY FEET TO DO THIS
AND THEY WOULD ACTUALLY DO THAT.
>> Jimmy: RIGHT.
YOU DON'T EVER DO IT ANYMORE?
>> NO, I DON'T.
I DON'T.
MY FIRST CLASS, THOUGH, I WALKED
INTO THE STUDIO.
IT'S ALL THESE LIKE 6-YEAR-OLDS,
7-YEAR-OLDS.
>> Jimmy: REALLY?
>> STRAIGHT UP, MAN.
STUDIO IN SANTA MONICA.
AND THESE KIDS ARE LOOKING AT ME
LIKE WHAT?
NO WAY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHAT'S THIS GROWN-ASS MAN DOING
IN HERE LEARNING TAP DANCE?
>> Jimmy: WOW.
THIS IS -- TAP DANCING.
YOU NEVER -- YOU WANT TO DO A
LITTLE TAP DANCE?
CAN YOU SHOW US A LITTLE?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> IF I COULD I WOULD.
>> Jimmy: WE'LL TAKE A BREAK.
GO GET COACHED -- GUILLERMO, GO
GET A GIANT PAIR OF TAP SHOES.
[ CROWD CHANTING "KOBE" ]
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> Jimmy: THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US TONIGHT ON THIS SAD NIGHT.
I WISH IT HAD BEEN UNDER HAPPIER
CIRCUMSTANCES.
MAGIC JOHNSON WILL BE WITH US
TOMORROW NIGHT ON THE SHOW.
AND AGAIN, IF YOU'D LIKE TO MAKE
A DONATION TO THE KOBE AND
VANESSA BRYANT FAMILY
FOUNDATION, YOU CAN DO IT AT THE
ADDRESS ON YOUR SCREEN.
WE PRAY FOR EVERYONE WHO WAS
LOST YESTERDAY AND THOSE THEY
LEFT BEHIND, THE CHILDREN, THEIR
PARENTS, AND KOBE BRYANT, WHO IS
GONE BUT WILL NEVER BE
FORGOTTEN.
>> KOBE BRYANT, FROM LOWER
MERION HIGH SCHOOL IN
PENNSYLVANIA.
♪
♪ TALK ABOUT
♪ TAKE THOSE PICTURES DOWN AND
SHAKE IT OUT ♪
♪ TRUTH OR CONSEQUENCE
♪ RACE IT AROUND
♪ THERE GOES MY HERO
♪ WATCH HIM AS HE GOES
♪ HE'S ORDINARY
♪ THERE GOES MY HERO
♪ WATCH HIM AS HE GOES
♪ HE'S ORDINARY